Joshua Ludwig

213 Bainbridge St, Philadelphia, PA

484-429-1584 jhludwig94@gmail.com joshludwig.com

OBJECTIVE

Analytical decision-maker with 2 years experience driving growth in a gritty early-stage start-up, seeking an opportunity where my adaptable thinking and determination will create value for both my organization and its users/clients. I want for my new role to strengthen my already strong foundations in digital analytics, and project management in an enthusiastic and motivated workplace.

EDUCATION/CERTIFICATIONS

University of Delaware

Bachelor of Science in Management Information Systems

May 2017

HIPPA

• HIPPA Security and HIPPA Privacy for Business, valid through 2021.

Google Analytics Academy

• Google Analytics for Power Users, valid through September 2022.

RELEVANT COURSEWORK

Statistics With R, Introduction to Probability and Data (Through Duke University) MISY 430/431: Applied Project Management

- Developed a form submission web app for the Department of Hospitality at the University of Delaware to log student service hours using agile methodology, improving data reporting/retention processes.
- Informed client with project management tools (Wireframes, Gantt Chart, Process Flows, User Stories, ERD Design).

WORK EXPERIENCE

VeryApt

Operations Manager

January 2018-Current

- Created listing contracts with large residential rental companies (roughly \$30,00 in annual revenues) and performed account management/retention for all rental clients that listed with me.
- Acted as the procuring agent in 100+ residential leases, maintaining a conversion rate above the targeted 10% of users that enter our system (roughly \$100,000 in annual revenues).
- Led weekly team meetings, identifying individual and team performance objectives, then defining and troubleshooting any business problems that impeded progress towards those benchmarks.
- Managed Drexel Co-op students for summer internships, guiding their productivity goals, personal development objectives, organizational on-boarding etc.
- Mastery of industry standard business technologies (Microsoft Outlook, Microsoft Project, Microsoft PowerPoint, Microsoft Excel, Trello, Slack, Docusign, Adobe Spark, GitHub).
- Reported to shareholders and executive management on traffic, profitability, growth, etc.
- Created hand-off documentation to solidify business processes that previously lacked material recording.

Hardwick Benfer LLC

Data Analyst

August 2017-December 2017

- Took source data (10,000+ records) provided by a Fortune 100 company in legal discovery and modeled using Excel (macros, vlookups with multiple criteria, pivot tables) to build a quantitative prosecution.
- Presented Data Studio visualizations to defense teams resulting in multiple pre-trial settlements.

John I. Weinberg Center for Corporate Governance

 $Corporate\ Governance\ Intern\ \&\ Teaching\ Assistant,\ Professor\ Charles\ Elson$

February 2015-May 2017

- Teaching Assistant for Professor Charles Elson's "Advanced Seminar in Corporate Governance" where I consulted students on term papers, designed and led review sessions, and graded examinations/papers.
- Led planning and execution of bi-annual Governance Symposiums (budgeting, logistics, venue reservation).

ACTIVITIES

Philabundance

Volunteer

January 2019-Current

 Accumulated 50 volunteer hours packing and organizing Hunger Relief Center boxes, with an estimated individual impact value of \$500 since starting.